Curriculum vitae - David Pettersson

Phone: +46 (0)76 049 95 31

E-mail: davidpetter@gmail.com

Summary

I am an IT Architect with a background in the insurance and fintech industry. I have experience from both architecture and development from different stacks. I genuinely believe that the key to efficiency is Autonomy, Mastery, and Purpose and that business value is achieved by speed of iteration. My contribution is to enable that transformation by providing technical leadership and business knowledge by coaching, guiding, teaching and leading by example.

Experience

TROI Arkitektur, Stockholm (August 2022 -) IT Architect.

IT Architect working with C More and TV4.

Relevant projects and initiatives

- Collaborating on an integration strategy.
- Participating in an evaluation of subscription management systems

Coop, Stockholm (May 2021 - November 2021) Solution Architect.

Solution architect for the payments and retail area.

SPP, Stockholm (June 2020 - April 2021) Security Manager.

Responsible for IT security in SPP. Tasks included making security reviews, guidelines for secure development and managing day to day security concerns.

AFA Försäkring, Stockholm (October 2017 - June 2020) IT Architect.

Part of the core architecture team working with enterprise, domain and solution architecture. Supporting the organization in general architectural matters regarding organization, processes, capabilities, services, and technology.

Relevant projects and initiatives

- Co-creating and implementing an IT Strategy.
- Setting architecture vision and guiding principles for the finance and claims departments.
- Architectural runway and technical lead in the transformation of the claims system from a monolith towards a distributed solution.
- Co-creating a security capability architecture and roadmap.

n vitae Phone: +46 (0)76 049 95 31tersson E-mail: davidpetter@gmail.com

- Solution architect finance department setting a new economic model and planning system.
- Solution architect for a greenfield reporting system in Azure.
- Defining architecture principles for API based integration.

ASSA ABLOY AB, Stockholm (January 2016 - October 2017) Software engineer.

ASSA ABLOY Mobile Services, a startup mode subsidiary supporting the ASSA ABLOY Group with mobile solutions related to access and identity. Creating a proprietary identity and credential solution based on Seos smart card protocol.

Projects and initiatives

- Developing a credential provisioning platform as well as related applications and systems.
- Solution architect for a mobile identity project, supporting both the backend and frontend team.
- Working with the migration from an on-premise monolith to a scalable cloud solution.
- Developing the Seos smart card capabilities such as ciphers and other functionality.
- ISO 27001 certification, part of the team working with the compliance process.

Accumulate AB, Stockholm (November 2011 - January 2016) Technical Lead.

Working with architecture, design, investigation, and implementation of platforms, IoT devices, POS and systems for mobile commerce, payment, banking, and security.

Responsibilities

- Team lead for a virtual development team of 8-10 developers located in Stockholm and Lviv.
- Technical lead for the payments, identity and credential platform working with both java backend and mobile frontend.
- Solution architect in implementations for customers such as PayPal, Arlanda Express, Tele2 Arena and PKO Bank.
- PCI DSS certification, part of the team working with the compliance process.

Sony Ericsson Mobile Communications AB, Lund (August 2008 - November 2011) Software Engineer.

Developing mobile applications for Sony Ericsson proprietary platform, based on OSE, and Android as well as maintaining the Android application framework. Client-side application development using Java, C++, and C.

Phone: +46 (0)76 049 95 31 E-mail: davidpetter@gmail.com

TietoEnator AB, Kalmar (January - August 2008) Software Engineer.

Creating software for managing phone number portability and virtual call centers. Server application development utilising Java EE, hibernate, HTML, javascript and .NET

Education

Master of Science in Engineering, Lund University, LTH (2003 - 2008)

Master of Science in Informations and Communications technology, specialisation in signal and image processing.

References

Given on request.